

ТО

REACH Media Dallas, TX

# POSITION

**Production Coordinator** 

# DATE

December 30, 2018

Hello REACH Media!

From extravagant costumes, to pink pom poms, I've spent my life cheerleading my friends and family and then organizing them into position during holiday photos. Who knew that in doing it, I'd find my calling: Production.

Here's what I could immediately bring to the table as a Production Coordinator at REACH Media.

Most people when let go from a job, spend a week or two licking their wounds. Not me. In the first twenty four hours, I had subscribed to more than a half dozen job boards, contacted local recruiters about open positions, and got a subscription for a teach-yourself-C++ programming course. This is the passion and drive I bring every day of the week.

I believe that a good producer not only acts as a bridge between those facets, but also between department teams - even down to the individual people. That's why when our company brought in remote workers from India, I made sure to schedule personal, daily meetings with them. Just because they weren't in the office didn't mean they mattered any less.

There will be times when the unexpected happens and you have to remain calm I believe the best way to do this is -knowing team/good rapport, maximizing the skill set of each individual, flexible jobs, a disposition for automation, and a well planned schedule.

Thank you for your time!

Macauley Hopper





## CONTACT

Mobile	(972) 567-5105
Email	mac_hopper@mac.com

## LINKS



www.macauleyhopper.com



www.linkedin.com/in/machopper

## Personal Statement

I love production, they help the culmination of so many different talented people from artists, to musicians, to actors and beyond. Seeing all aspects come together to create a finished product is an amazing and rewarding experience. In my spare time I like attending local meetups and talking with other people in the industry. Creative work is a huge aspect of my life, helping craft unique and engaging works for viewers that they will continue to talk about for years to come.

# Professional Experience

## 2018

### Digital Producer - Contract

Cactex Media, Dallas, TX - October 2018 - December 2018

- · Created detailed timelines, wire frames, menu mockups, and wire layouts
- Kept track of multiple applications requirements
- Helped record individuals and cut and convert the audio for presentation use
- · Worked with a team and stakeholders to stay on schedule and solve any and all roadblocks
- Developed storyboards for video and demos

## Configuration Management Engineer

XO Communications, Plano, TX - October 2014 - March 2018

- $\bullet \ Created\ documentation\ for\ various\ applications, including\ Git,\ Source Tree,\ Tortoise\ Git,\ and\ Team\ Foundation\ Server.$
- Managed Agile development process, hosting daily scrums with 10 developers.
- Provided support for Git development tool and build environments

# Personal Projects

#### Producer & Designer - A.R.C.H.O.N

Tiny Tyrants, Plano, TX - January 2015 - Present

- Designed the destructible environment mechanic, event card system, and all armor and weapons.
- Studied and maintained target demographic studies for optimal customer reach.
- Led play testing sessions, and designed and balanced the armor and weapon systems

# Producer & Designer - Five Suns

Studio Hue, Savannah, GA - January 2014 - June 2014

 $\bullet \ \, \text{Designed the moment-to-moment gameplay, including the combat system, enemy classes, and spell sets. }$ 

 $\bullet \ Collaborated \ with \ artists \ to \ ensure \ the \ armor \ pieces \ and \ we apons \ were \ able \ to \ work \ with \ the \ players' \ ARCHON \ cards.$ 

- · Led play testing and daily scrum sessions, and oversaw cast and crew production schedule.
- Presented results of the play testing sessions to various departmental personnel.
- Directly responsible for all project deadlines, including all art assets, design principals, voice work, and casting.
- Received Entelechy 2014 Best 2D Game Award.



## Producer & Designer - Vallo

Savannah College of Art and Design, Savannah, GA - September 2013 - November 2013

- Designed a RTS RPG Tower Defense game
- · Worked with 2 freelance artists to help create concept art for the project
- Producer & Designer Flight of the Meridian

Savannah College of Art and Design, Savannah, GA - September 2013 - November 2013

- Designed a 3 versus 1 board game
- Worked with 2 freelance artists to help create concept art for the project

# EDUCATION



Savannah, College of Art and Design, Savannah GA Bachelor of Fine Arts in Interactive Design and Game Development 2014

# SOFTWARE

Autodesk Maya Jira Unreal Development Kit Team Foundation Server Adobe Creative Suite Git Google Product Suite Microsoft Office